<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Philosophy on f(x) </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Firo Yang</author>
    
    <updated>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Nihilism</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/nihilism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/nihilism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;虚无主义本质上是逻辑问题， 首先虚无主义者， 无法证明某种自己期望的意义的存在。 但这不能否定这种（生命/希望/生活/为之奋斗）的意义的存在的可能， 所以虚无主义者都被用身为人类的本能和自我意识不断思考而编成的绳子悬挂在这个世界。 稍有不慎这个绳子就可能断了， 走向死亡。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;无论虚无主义者多么绝望， 都不能理智层面上 否定 他所期望的意义的存在的可能。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;所以这个世界是可能存在意义的， 而不是彻底的无意义， 因为我们无法证明所有的事都是无意义的。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;依据我个人的感受， 虚无主义者并不是真的不想做任何事， 而是在内心深处， 认为这个世界不配；不能实心实意的把自己交给这个世界&amp;ndash; 依我来看&amp;ndash; 这个世界， 虽然历经人类数千年的打磨， 依然在物质和精神层面而言都是荒野/荒原。 人类被随意的放在这个荒野之中。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;虚无主义者， 只是真诚的思考者。 绝不是虚无主义者内心空虚，而是现在这个世界的虚无，没有给虚无主义者提供足够的意义， 才导致人成为虚无主义者。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我们的虚无源自于我们的软弱。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;个人的力量始终是有限的， 这个世界上受虚无主义影响的人毕竟是少数， 所以虚无主义者们应该联合到一起， 透过科学的手段 去弄明白世界为什么存在。 很多虚无主义者会死在这个过程中。这是身为而人的短暂生命的悲哀。 虚无主义者应该拥有跨越千万年的生命， 因为很多时候我们舍弃了很多现实的诉求。 所以我们可能需要汇聚跨越数个世代的虚无主义者群体， 最终来完成这个目标。 了解世界为什么存在能找到所有事情的起源， 也就是意义的最开始，揭开所有的谜底 。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;同时， 可能存在某种意义， 某种创造者希望我们， 去完成的， 在未来等着我们。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;虚无主义并不全然是悲观的坏处， 至少他否定权威， 这会让我们在现实生活中和理性层面获得更多的自由， 减少某些欺骗导致的苦难。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;不可避免， 身为人， 虚无主义者， 为了找到某种意义， 我们要好好的活着， 尽管， 内心不能认同那是我们的意义， 但这是这片大地给我的馈赠&amp;ndash;自由，同事伴随而来的副产品， 束缚。 身为人的大地的束缚。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;虚无主义者, 很容易忽视自己的感受. 相对其他人类而言, 我们更容易委屈自己. 纯粹的理性逻辑的思维中, 现实与思想的联系被割裂, 更容易陷入思维的泥沼里, 难以自拔. 自己成为某种意义的前提条件, 所以搞懂自己就时必须的. 虚无主义者的阵地就是理性思维, 而来自外界感受, 易被忽视.自己至少是由理性思维和对外在的感受共同组成的.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我不认同虚无主义只是纯粹主观的理性问题，但逻辑会帮我们理顺问题。从某种程度上，这是一个客观现实的问题。由此看来虚无主义是理性和现实共同引发的问题。理性可以容易通过能指表示问题，甚至不惧任何意义，而在浩如烟海的现实世界，人无迹所踪。甚至导致以为虚无主义是纯粹主观的理性的问题。从而忽略现实， 甚至忽略来自外界的感受， 既然外界的感受会是我们的意义的一部分， 了解自己的主观感受，使之达到就如同理性层面的批判的健康状态。当然我们不知道达到健康的主观感受对于我们寻找意义有如何的帮助。 我们只是在寻找意义的过程中。所谓的健康状态，从思维层面看体现的是理性的，批判的和潜在的自由的。主观感受要达到什么样状态呢？首先，是不应限制 约束理性层面的健康状态。 我们存在的基础就是, 我们理性中的自我意识. 我是谁, 谁是我. 个体的意识在外在的世界的影响想不断形成.可以说个人的意识,就是世界的意识. 世界本身也在寻找他的意志. 我是我, 我也是世界的一份.  同时世界也是矛盾的, 各种意识相互影响. 个体自身的意识, 使之遵循自身意义成为可能. 应当维护自身.  在这个世界上, 每个人都在追寻自己的意义, 可能是不自觉, 亦或是有目标， 但总之其他人的意义会影响我们，竞争是如此激烈，以致这个世界在阳光之下潜藏着满满地恶，偶尔包不住了，会泄漏出来。 所以维持自己的存在，对于人生来说格外重要， 这是所有的意义。 而生命中那些不能承受的轻，时不时的成为自我委屈的导火索。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;现实的感受对于维持个体主观意志的健康，是如此的必要。并非吹毛求疵。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;做到如此， 一个真正的自我，便浮现出来。 这边是人生意义所应该表述的内在，即我们在最大程度上保证自身的自由与健康，个人意志的最大程度的伸展与表述，即这是我们期待的自己。 反抗一切形式的压迫。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;搜寻生命的意义。 拥有未自省的人生的人，他所追寻的目标意义，很大程度上，是世界赋予的也就是 世界的意志 自身的本能的体现， 而并非自己真正的意图，也即Griffith 所言 有些人终其一生都不知为何而活，最终慢慢飘出这个世界。 又言 被梦想所奴役。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;相较于纯粹的理性思维，生命， 是否值得一个意义？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;那么多远大的意义 为什么不能给生命一个？&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;生命/人生的意义不应该是唯一的.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;追寻自由，独立的意志&lt;br /&gt;
反抗剥削，压迫，奴役&lt;br /&gt;
反抗与逃离那些不被注意，却无处不在，弥漫在这个个社会上潜移默化地，悄无声息的使人变得畸形，制约个人自由的生长， 噤若寒蝉， 放弃生命本身自然的约束&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>荒野中的人</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/the_wilds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 20:23:11 CST</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/the_wilds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;国家是所有怪物中最为冷酷的, 冷酷的谎言从头的嘴里爬出来:&amp;ldquo;我, 这个国家, 就是全体人民.&lt;br /&gt;
                                ———— 尼采 《新的偶像》&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一个人在降生之前, 他的同类, 就以国家这个怪物的名义瓜分了这个他所赖以生存世界,&lt;br /&gt;
没有选择的余地. 是的, 无论你是否愿意, 你都将成为国家的一部分. 同时, 这也是&lt;br /&gt;
个人乃至整个人类族群的悲剧的起源!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人们不可避免的成为了社会的一个螺丝钉, 你要生存就必须参与进来.&lt;br /&gt;
生活在所谓社会中的个体, 又是怎样的? 普遍特征就是放弃思考!&lt;br /&gt;
在面对历经数千年历史形成的庞大社会体系, 对于个人来说, 了解适应&lt;br /&gt;
这个社会占据了他的一生. 只要少数人不断常识改变, 革新人们所处的生活&lt;br /&gt;
牢笼, 如卢梭, 孟德斯鸠, 尼采, 马克思等等.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我发现, 所处社会中绝大多数人, 都觉得他的being, 以及围绕他的一切都是理所当然.&lt;br /&gt;
所有的人, 都在顺从着社会的意志, 成为社会的奴隶. 而社会中的绝大多数人成为了一小部分&lt;br /&gt;
人的奴隶.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellecutual</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/intellectual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/intellectual/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most General and comprehensive type of inquiry(what is true and why)&lt;br /&gt;
Epistemology is theory of knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Metaphysics is the theory of reality.&lt;br /&gt;
Epistemic realism: the view that our knowledge is true of its objects independent of our ideas, theories, and cultures.&lt;br /&gt;
Antirealism/relativism: our true knowledge is made true not byobjects independent of us, but by our own ideas, perspectives, theories, and cultures.&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic philosophy:&lt;br /&gt;
Continental philosophy:&lt;br /&gt;
Pragmatism:&lt;br /&gt;
Tempered view:&lt;br /&gt;
Scholasticism: philosophy of the schools was based Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s logic and metaphysics; is essentially aristotle plus Christianity&lt;br /&gt;
Scholastic: what they did no have in their religious thouht was an elaborate complex theory of nature in the natural world.&lt;br /&gt;
Primary being/substance/the underlying:physical objects; contains parts but is not a pat of anything;properties are predicated of it, but it is not predicated of any thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Doctrine of the four causes: Aristotle generalize ideal objects, atomism to a very famous doctrine: the material, the efficient, the formal, the final.&lt;br /&gt;
Soul: the animating principle, not the Christian notion of soul, not an eternal ongoing non-physical essence.&lt;br /&gt;
Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s three levels of soul: 1 vegetative soul, characteristic of plants. 2. Moving-senstive-passionate soul, characteristic of animals. 3. rational soul, charteristic of .&lt;br /&gt;
CGN: the only way to udnerstand these objects in this world is to turn away from your experience of them, form how they look day to day and instead pay attention to an ideal mathematical reconstruction of those objects.&lt;br /&gt;
Rape of the senses: Morden science does not accord with our unaided senses, it accords with mathematical theory of potentially unobservable entities that explain our sense experience in the other words the new platonic but experimental science replaced the Aristotelian quanlitative and purpose of science that have become integrated whith Christian thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;descartes&#34;&gt;Descartes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archimedean point for all knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
Cogito ergo sum: I think, therefore I exist.&lt;br /&gt;
I: non-physical, thinking subsatnce.&lt;br /&gt;
extened substance/spatial extension&lt;br /&gt;
solipsist:&lt;br /&gt;
God must exists.&lt;br /&gt;
For Descartes, Reality is composed of:finite material substatnces, the essence of which is to take up space; finite mental substances, hunman minds and the human soul;on infinite mental substance, God.&lt;br /&gt;
Minds are non spatial thinking things without parts.Something without parts cannot come apart it can not decay. Imortal soul.&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes has thus provided a means a powerfull means of separating physical material reality which will noew be the province of the new science the materialist mechanical science of nature that comes especially from Galileo. The mind which is also the soul the seat of emotions which is also the seat of my own free will and hence responsible for ethics. It belongs to these fields and can&amp;rsquo;t be studied by science.&lt;br /&gt;
The best cognitive method God has given us we must be right otherwise God just is a deceiver.&lt;br /&gt;
The field of evidence presented to my individual mind is the foundation of all evidence for any claim.&lt;br /&gt;
Foundationalism: the belief that philosophy&amp;rsquo;s job jis to discover the foudndation or ground of all realist, objective knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;john-locke&#34;&gt;John Locke&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An essay concerning human understanding(1690)&lt;br /&gt;
an empty cabinet/a blank slate&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s basic categories(all possible properties that anything in the world can have): extension, solidity, motivity, mobility, perceptivity ot thinking, existence, duration, number.&lt;br /&gt;
Primary qualities: in the subject(in my mind) and in the object size, volume, mass, velocity, number.&lt;br /&gt;
Secondary qualities : color, taste, sound&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge: awareness of the agreement or disagreement of ideas with one another.&lt;br /&gt;
The awareness or knowledge comes in three different forms.&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition: the immediate recognition of the likenees or unlikeness of two ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
Senastion: feeling the entrance of ideas from sensation entering the mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Logical demostration or argument: Linking ideas together in such a way that there is a relationship of logical entailment or deduction.&lt;br /&gt;
 Unknown support.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s method: a posteriori; based on facts about the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes&amp;rsquo;s method: could not use a posteriori agruments because he had doubted the existence of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;berkeley&#34;&gt;Berkeley&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idealism: Reality is in some sense mental or the product of mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Interactions of mind and body:1. material events must be able to cause bodily and neural brain events. 2. Ideas in the mind must be able to represent things in the world that caused them; otherwise we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Ideas cannot represent material objects.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s Primary quailites: ideas in the mind taht represet and resemble the same quality in the material object, like zie&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s secondary qualities: caused by material events but don&amp;rsquo;t resemble them, like color.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke and Descartes: we perceive representations(ideas of things) outside our mind - representationalism&lt;br /&gt;
Berkeley: Where do representations exist? in our mind.&lt;br /&gt;
To be is to be percived.&lt;br /&gt;
Direct realism, the claim that we experience objects independent of the independent of the mind, is false.&lt;br /&gt;
Representationalism, the claim that we experience mental objects, but that these mental objects represent objects independent of the mind, is also false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;neo-aristotelians-spinoza-and-leibnizg&#34;&gt;Neo Aristotelians - Spinoza and Leibnizg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spinoza&#34;&gt;Spinoza&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole of everything: the only substance can be independent; the whole of existence is numerically one substance.&lt;br /&gt;
Immanent notions of God: somehow identify God with the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Transcendent notitons of God: see God as separate from the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Pantheist: an extreme form of immanentist.Infinite mentality and materialityand phisicality.&lt;br /&gt;
Panentheist: Nature is in God, but God is more than Nature. Spinoza.&lt;br /&gt;
Psychophysical parallelism: dimensions of the one. Mental events and physical events are co-ordinated in respectively minds and bodies.&lt;br /&gt;
Stoicism: apathy, apathos: the control of pathos, the control of emotion;&lt;br /&gt;
Ethics: magnum opus; the goal of human life and the highest state the mind can aspire to is a dispassionate intellectual love of God and a recognition of necessity and consequently as in Stoicism an internal state of calm acceptance rather than disturbed attachment to the faded events of this world. Spinoza is stauch critic of anthropomorphization of God. God can love this world but God has no free will and can not be conceived of as anything like a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;leibnizg&#34;&gt;Leibnizg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polymath, jack of all intellectual traists. Inaugurated the modern German philosophical tradition.&lt;br /&gt;
Monads: cannot causally interact; contain entelechy; phylogenetic thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Entelechy: an inner principle that unfolds all the changes it goes through with respect to other substances.&lt;br /&gt;
Bare monads: minimal appetition and perception.&lt;br /&gt;
souls: animal monads; cue ball is inanimate, but rabbit has soul.&lt;br /&gt;
Spirits: Monads with the property of apperception/统觉. essentially whtat that means is consciousness the ability to reflect on it&amp;rsquo;s own perceptions.SO here we have minds in our sense of the word(world?) that is human minds which capable of rational thought and they have a self now.&lt;br /&gt;
Space and time: continual and mere appearance; do not exist without the presence of monads.posthumous revenge on Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-enlightenment&#34;&gt;The Enlightenment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God said, &amp;ldquo;Let Newton be,&amp;rsquo; and there was light. - Alexander Pope&lt;br /&gt;
Encycolpedists&lt;br /&gt;
Spontaneous order: beneficial order that could be the product of undesigned activity: no one controls; only background rules govern independent action; no coordination among actions; beneficent order emerges.&lt;br /&gt;
Amour propre:the love of self as it is seen by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dvaid-hume&#34;&gt;Dvaid Hume&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of relations of ideas: the relations one idea bears to another in my mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge of matters of fact&lt;br /&gt;
Constant cojunction:Whenever A has occurred, B has occurred.&amp;ldquo;Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve seen smoke, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen fire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Necessary connection:If I say A and B are necesarily connected then I say not merely whenever A hsa occurred, B has occured. But I say Whenever A occurs B must occur: 1 whenever A occurs, A has the power to make B occur; 2 whenever A occurs in the future, B will occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;kant&#34;&gt;Kant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critique of pure reason:the theory of knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Critique of pratical reason: ethics.&lt;br /&gt;
Critique of judgment: aesthetics(theory of art), teleology(purpose in nature).&lt;br /&gt;
A priori: independent of experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Hume&amp;rsquo;s category of relations of ideas are both a priori and analytic.&lt;br /&gt;
Hume&amp;rsquo;s matters of fact are aposteriori and synthetic, or not true by definition.&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic: predicate conatained in subject&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic: predicate not in subject&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic a posteriori: Hume&amp;rsquo;s matters of fact; Belgium contains bachelors&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic a priori: Hume&amp;rsquo;s relations of ideas; All bachelors are unmarried.&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic apriori:non-trivial knowledge valid independent of experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Transcendental: the pre-structuring of experience by the mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Kant&amp;rsquo;s cognitive faculty:intuition, or sensibility, understanding, and reason.o&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition&amp;rsquo;s a priori forms: space, time&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding&amp;rsquo;s a priori categories: e.g., substances and their properties; necessary connection.&lt;br /&gt;
synthetic a priori knowledge: space,time;necessary connection; substance ( subject and predicate);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;karl-poper&#34;&gt;Karl Poper&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience or observations do not confirm scientific or inductive hypotheses. The function of induction is not to confirme; it is to disconfirm hpotheses.&lt;br /&gt;
Falsificationism: evidence really can&amp;rsquo;t confront any theory it can only falsify theory and this would mean that scientific claims are highly fallible&lt;br /&gt;
Fallibilism: All our judgments are fallible.&lt;br /&gt;
Physicalist reductionism: the view that all scientific knowledge should in principle be reducible to physics as the most basic science.&lt;br /&gt;
British Emergentists: the whole has properties that are more thatn so to speak to some of the parts and in effect what the emergence said was for example the properties of chemistry can&amp;rsquo;t be deduced from the properties of physical systems the properties of biology.&lt;br /&gt;
Positivism: quantum mechanics,&lt;br /&gt;
Supervenience: While any chage in mental events or properties must presuppose a change in nerual events or properties, the mental events or properties could still not be reduced to or explained by, neural events alone&lt;br /&gt;
Teleological causality: when a creature with a mind has an idea, and that idea has a causal relationship to what it does.&lt;br /&gt;
The structure of scientific revolutions: Whig interpertation of the history science&lt;br /&gt;
Prardigm: the fundamental concepts and practices of a science in a period of time.&lt;br /&gt;
Kuhn held that the meanings of the terms used in observation and theory in any period of normal science are dependent on that holistic paradigm&lt;br /&gt;
incommensurable: mutually untranslatable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pragmatism&#34;&gt;Pragmatism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;phenomenology&#34;&gt;Phenomenology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the things themselves.&lt;br /&gt;
bracketing: suspension of judgment.&lt;br /&gt;
eidetic reduction&lt;br /&gt;
transendental ego&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;derrida&#34;&gt;Derrida&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;semiosis: sign-using; the study of signs.&lt;br /&gt;
signs we use are arbitrary; signs are exterior or material -not solely mental.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>人类世界</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/human/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 15:46:11 CST</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;世界被他人的谎言所掩盖, 丧失了原始的存在欲望.`&lt;br /&gt;
一点点小的改变, 事情就会朝着好的方向发展.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一个人应该与外界的应该保持什么样的关系? 每个人都应该有自己的回答, 而且答案不一而终.&lt;br /&gt;
正是这种关系成就了我们的一生.个体如何确定这种关系,或者说如何确定一种合理的生存状态?&lt;br /&gt;
对于人类丰富, 无止尽的欲望而言, 很难给出统一的答案.然而这并不妨碍我们找到理想的状态.&lt;br /&gt;
简单说来, 两点; 那些来自内心的, 原始的, 本能的愿望正是我们生活的方向, 不应被忽视, 反而&lt;br /&gt;
要经常回忆起来, 并视若内心的珍宝一样对待; 另外, 我们应该做的是弥补生活中的不足, 以此来&lt;br /&gt;
向理想中的生活不断的迈进, 而不是沉醉于对理想的执着与等待中. 从实实在在的生活不足开始,&lt;br /&gt;
这才是真实的, 是你的生活.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;生活不在别处, 正是当下此地.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对于世界一部分的个体, 充分的认识世界的运作机制, 成为确定自己生活状态的前提. 对于普通人&lt;br /&gt;
而言, 这似乎无从下手. 尤其是对于处在巨大生存压力下的人, 无暇顾及这般如同象牙塔式的问题?&lt;br /&gt;
我想这正是他们生活悲剧的根源之一. 对于了解这个世界, 实际上要简单许多. 我想, 只要你有意识&lt;br /&gt;
地在遇到困惑, 疑问, 艰难, 令人不适的生活的时候, 寻找这些问题背后的原因的时候, 答案便会出现.&lt;br /&gt;
而答案就是一种关系, 因果律. 同时连带得出关系的主客体. 比如, 49年后, 中国人都有一个潜在&lt;br /&gt;
的伟大的身份, 社会主义建造者.这是个体和国家之间的某种答案,在我出生之时, 变自动获得这种身份.&lt;br /&gt;
直到我意识到这种身份的存在时, 我毫不犹豫的放弃了它.因为我并不是一个社会主义者,&lt;br /&gt;
我打心眼里抵触社会主义, 我很难想象他的存在, 同时那样的社会对我来说是一种无声的恐惧,&lt;br /&gt;
因为他偏离人性的核心, 那样的社会下的生活, 我一点也不期待, 我已体验过了.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;显然, 在人与世界的诸多联系中, 有一些是被他人赋予, 而那些强制赋予的很多都成了枷锁.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对于确定生命个体的合理生存状态, 可以看成找到你与世界现有的关系以及想要的某种关系.&lt;br /&gt;
首先, 我们要理清那些重要的关系. 可以说我的哲学就是建立在关系之上, 也就是因果律.&lt;br /&gt;
人总生活在关系中, 我认为下面的关系很重要.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从个人角度, 越靠近真实, 越靠近真实, 不靠近就会远离. 这也是因果律的体现.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;即便你找不到期待中的生活状态，你也活在关系中, 这也是最基本的．&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人生没有目标, 也要好好活着!&lt;br /&gt;
所有人都是某些东西的奴隶 &amp;ndash; 进击的巨人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其他的规律：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;＞正反合&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 完整的逻辑,包含不存在&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 生活就是同傻逼的战争!&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 每个人都有自己内心的弱点, 不必害怕他们.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 生长需要滋润.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 成长开始于注意到缺陷, 疑问&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 很多时候其实我们的忙碌都是做着自己并不在乎的事情！&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 生命所不能承受之轻!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unknown philosophy</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/epistemology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/epistemology/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;unknown&#34;&gt;Unknown&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Causality, Reality, dynamic, Chaos, abyss, unknown, Thing-in-itself, Universal connection, Life, Uncertainty, Reality, Effect and Inefficiency, change/process, complexicity, Atifragile, the invisiable world&lt;br /&gt;
Matter, space, Enegy, force, Time, Motion, The invisiable world and desymbolize. Conflicts. Problems world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;causality&#34;&gt;Causality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_causes&#34;&gt;Aristotle:we don&amp;rsquo;t have knowledge of a thing until we have grasped its why, that is to say, its cause&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=36GT2zI8lVA&#34;&gt;Richard Feynman. Why.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;chaos&#34;&gt;Chaos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;don’t try to make it logical&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;time&#34;&gt;Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easier to invent future than to predict it. — Alan Kay&lt;br /&gt;
Strategy is the art of making use of time and space. I am less chary of the latter than the former. Space we can recover, lost time never. —Napoleon Bonaparte&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline-history&#34;&gt;Timeline, history&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;complexcity&#34;&gt;Complexcity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No silver bullet. The Mythical Man-Month, Object-Oriented Analysis and Design with Applications, The philosophy of software design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;detail-complexcity-and-dynamic-complexcity-chapter-20-rewriting-the-code-of-the-fifith-discipline&#34;&gt;Detail complexcity and dynamic complexcity - chapter 20 Rewriting the Code of The Fifith discipline.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-complete-2&#34;&gt;Code complete 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my view, it’s so important that Software’s Primary Technical Imperative has to be managing complexity.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;hellip; Dijkstra pointed out that no one’s skull is really big enough to contain a modern computer program (Dijkstra 1972 The Humble Programmer), which means that we as software developers shouldn’t try to cram whole programs into our skulls at once; we should try to organize our programs in such a way that we can safely focus on one part of it at a time. The goal is to minimize the amount of a program you have to think about at any one time. You might think of this as mental juggling—the more mental balls the program requires you to keep in the air at once, the more likely you’ll drop one of the balls, leading to a design or coding error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;structure&#34;&gt;Structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole is other than the sum of the parts. &amp;ndash;Gestalt psychology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;model-of-thinking-linus-torvalds-talking-with-aalto-university-students-11-00-https-www-youtube-com-watch-v-pdece3mtkrg&#34;&gt;Model of thinking - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PDEce3mtkRg&#34;&gt;Linus Torvalds talking with Aalto University students 11:00&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fern-chaos-theory&#34;&gt;Fern, Chaos theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-other&#34;&gt;The other&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;life&#34;&gt;Life&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Physical(including Biology) and mental world; subjective building and role based knowledge vs Subjectivity. In-thing vs Out-observing. Protection and Tidy; top-down vs bottom-up; de-symblize smantic and express yourself; mental arbitrariness vs physical concidence; relative knowledge and relative essence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;independence&#34;&gt;Independence&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;什么是独立呢?“独立”是你们自己的事，给你自由而不独立这是奴隶，独立要不盲从，不受欺骗，不依傍门户，不依赖别人，不用别人耳朵为耳朵，不以别人的脑子为脑子，不用别人的眼睛为眼睛，这就是独立的精神。 &amp;ndash; 胡适在北京大学1946年开学演讲&lt;br /&gt;
The development of general ability for independent thinking and judgement should always be placed foremost, not the acquisition of special knowledge. -on education, Albert Einstein&lt;br /&gt;
If you don&amp;rsquo;t control yourself, you will be controlled by the Other. In turn, you lose yourself. - Firo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-abilities&#34;&gt;Mental abilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Locke, An Essay Concerning Human Understanding: The acts of the mind, wherein it exerts its power over simple ideas, are chiefly these three: 1. Combining ideas [&amp;hellip;] 2. [..] it gets all its ideas of relations. 3. The third is separating them from all other ideas that accompany them in their real existence: this is called abstraction, and thus all its general ideas are made.&lt;br /&gt;
Abstraction and concrete. &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.medium.com/TqmKU622u1&#34;&gt;由為什麼 “abstraction”不應該譯為“抽象化”談正名&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Generalization&#34;&gt;Generalization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;energy-and-life-expectancy&#34;&gt;Energy and Life expectancy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the conditions for reading what is good is that we must not read what is bad; for life is short and time and energy are limited. - Schopenhauver on reading and books&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;knowledge&#34;&gt;Knowledge&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;活知识; the ability of Swim and learning of history; Define the question, restore to life and causlaity; Architecture: common causes for many effects. Just for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;relative-knowledge&#34;&gt;Relative knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on how well we understand this world; don&amp;rsquo;t pursue a objective knowledge of this world.&lt;br /&gt;
Role-based understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;unknown-1&#34;&gt;Unknown&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; Time:   coward, timebound
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unknown:     Plan, goal, grow by mistakes, feedback&lt;br /&gt;
         Actual problems and actions&lt;br /&gt;
         Raw(high level, mode, complete)&lt;br /&gt;
     Method: Meaning: 在意不在形, sensemaking not analyzing, constructivism, root cause, First principles&lt;br /&gt;
         Small&lt;br /&gt;
         Bawan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     最初的悸动
     stupor, sea beach vacation
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;unknown, actual problems, plan, grow by actual mistakes, sensemaking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;will-cause-goals-plan-project&#34;&gt;Will - cause, goals, Plan, project.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do what you really want to do. If you want to do something, but you are afraid to do it, then that is likely what you should do.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cirosantilli.com/#dont-be-a-pussy&#34;&gt;Don’t be a pussy&lt;/a&gt;. 牛人心态: 牛人姿态, 会成为牛人, 研究东西，牛人洞察力，牛人水准, 研发出来的需要实战、需要工程化，否则只是玩具，而不能成为真的武器&lt;br /&gt;
不是有希望才做, 是做了才有希望. &amp;ndash; twitter June 4.&lt;br /&gt;
自己变厉害， 会遇见更厉害的人。&lt;br /&gt;
Mind the starter of causality: good order, expection, problem, goals, weakness, detest, disgust, all things should covered by causality including understanding Linux kernel. whatt is my goal?&lt;br /&gt;
法乎其上,得乎其中,法乎其中,仅得其下&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;actual-problems&#34;&gt;Actual problems&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language must be restored to real life. &amp;ndash; Ludwig Wittgenstein&lt;br /&gt;
I have never thought about questions that are not real ones - I have not squandered myself. &amp;ndash; N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;raw&#34;&gt;Raw&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framework, blurry -&amp;gt; concrete, detail&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;grow-by-mistakes&#34;&gt;Grow by mistakes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Challenge: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oCkkjnpS2f8&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oCkkjnpS2f8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bawan-just-for-fun-grow-by-bawan&#34;&gt;Bawan, just for fun, grow by bawan&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;put things in causlity not in mind.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TjaM0tdxtYA&#34;&gt;Why I Don’t Use A Smart Phone | Ann Makosinski | TEDxTeen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;small-and-simplicity&#34;&gt;Small and simplicity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;gradually grow up a little bit each day.&lt;br /&gt;
记少不记多,反而记更多; 时间是否充裕,都先记少. So I saw the less is more in action: the more studies, the less obvious elementary but fundamental things become; activity, on the other hand, strips things to their simplest possible model. &amp;ndash; Antifragile, Nassim. First, we can do it. Second, less will make more because we know the foundations before other things. 基础的简单的事.&lt;br /&gt;
Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes&amp;rsquo;s methods: Main/primary causes and secondary causes, Essential causes and additional causes;&lt;br /&gt;
Complete: MECE (Mutually Exclusive and Collectively Exhaustive).&lt;br /&gt;
Analogy: successful cases analysis and Transforming.&lt;br /&gt;
Feynman technique. Centric and stereoscopic Thinking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;scientific-method&#34;&gt;Scientific method&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=B9XGUpQZY38&#34;&gt;Principles For Success by Ray Dalio (In 30 Minutes)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Hypothesize bravely/boldly, to prove carefully &amp;ndash; Hushi&lt;br /&gt;
Reflexivity, critical thinking, unended quest. Reflexivity &amp;ndash; Soros; Hyposis and test. Trail and error.&lt;br /&gt;
SMART, SWOT: strengths, weaknesses, opportunities, threats.&lt;br /&gt;
Scale/&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Level_of_analysis&#34;&gt;level&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Chronicle facts describing: Onset, nuclus, coda. Beginner, intermediate, advanced. Time Archaeology&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wikihow.com/Create-an-Effective-Action-Plan&#34;&gt;How to Create an Effective Action Plan:  The less clear you are about what you want to do, the less effective your plan will be. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Leave questions open: There are always some knowledge which is too complicated to understand and we should leave them alone.&lt;br /&gt;
Pragmatism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;observability-have-fun&#34;&gt;Observability - Have fun.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;metric&#34;&gt;Metric&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firo: There are many levels of creation, e.g. a blank piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;feedback-and-mistakes&#34;&gt;Feedback and mistakes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delay &amp;ndash; The fifth discipline&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;end-of-times-of-analyzing-end-of-lack-causes-and-processes-of-mine-end-of-static-frozen-fixed-whole-knowledge-via-logical-positivism&#34;&gt;End of times of analyzing. End of lack causes and processes of mine.End of static frozen fixed whole knowledge via Logical Positivism.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dynamic knowledge; Reflexivity&lt;br /&gt;
大部分人从学校，从书籍，从文献学知识，结果学到一堆“死知识”。要检验知识是不是死的，很简单。如果你遇到前所未见的问题，却不能把这些知识运用出来解决问题，那么这些知识就很可能是死的。 &amp;ndash; wangyin&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;meaning&#34;&gt;Meaning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;直觉,图形. 在意不在形, sensemaking&lt;br /&gt;
Just as the largest library, badly arranged, is not so useful as a very moderate one that is well arranged, so the greatest amount of knowledge, if not elaborated by our own thoughts, is worth much less than a far smaller volume that has been abundantly and repeatedly thought over. The difference between the effect produced on the mind by thinking for oneself and that produced by reading is &lt;strong&gt;incredibly great&lt;/strong&gt;; and thus it is for ever &lt;strong&gt;increasing the original disparity between minds&lt;/strong&gt;, by virtue whereof we are driven to the one or to the other. Thus reading forces on the mind ideas that are as foreign and heterogeneous to the tendency and mood it has at the moment, as is the seal to the wax whereon it impresses its stamp. Thus the mind is totally compelled from without to think first of one thing and &lt;strong&gt;then of another, for which it has absolutely no inclination or disposition.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;hellip; Therefore the &lt;strong&gt;mind is deprived of all its elasticity by much reading&lt;/strong&gt; as is a spring when a weight is continually applied to it; This practice is the reason why &lt;strong&gt;erudition makes most men more stupid and simple than they are by nature and also deprives their literary careers of every success.&lt;/strong&gt; - Schopenhauer Parerga and Paralipomena Vol.2 Chapter XXII&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;constructivism&#34;&gt;Constructivism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;从结构主义走向建构主义的课程观及其启示.pdf&lt;br /&gt;
Constructivism: 意义建构理论(Sense-Making Theory) and Failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;connection-relevance&#34;&gt;Connection relevance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;管子, list_for_each_entry connections&lt;br /&gt;
put things in causlity not in mind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-principle-then-minimum-essential-fundamentals&#34;&gt;First principle, then minimum essential fundamentals.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I tend to approach things from a physics framework,” Musk said in an interview. “Physics teaches you to reason from first principles rather than by analogy. So I said, okay, let’s look at the first principles. What is a rocket made of? Aerospace-grade aluminum alloys, plus some titanium, copper, and carbon fiber. Then I asked, what is the value of those materials on the commodity market? It turned out that the materials cost of a rocket was around two percent of the typical price.” - Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;learning-by-doing-creating-what-you-did-defines-you-reinvent-creating-using&#34;&gt;Learning by doing/creating - what you did defines you. reinvent, creating, using.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1AbCS5qgAg1_ak7viwlE-g10z_8PmW1Hu/view?usp=sharing&#34; alt=&#34;one of Hushi&#39;s effort&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Talk:Leonardo_da_Vinci&#34;&gt;Leonardo da Vinci&lt;/a&gt;: I have been impressed with the urgency of doing. Knowing is not enough; we must apply. Being willing is not enough; we must do.&lt;br /&gt;
Aristotle, The Nicomachean Ethics: For the things we have to learn before we can do them, we learn by doing them.&lt;br /&gt;
Feynman mean: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-did-Richard-Feynman-mean-when-he-said-What-I-cannot-create-I-do-not-understand&#34;&gt;What I cannot create, I do not understand?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Goethe: 我们必须流下热汗, 才能真正拥有父亲留下的遗产.&lt;br /&gt;
Ray Dalio: knowing how to deal well with you setbacks is as important as knowing how to move forward.&lt;br /&gt;
John Dewey: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thepositiveencourager.global/john-deweys-approach-to-doing-positive-work/&#34;&gt;D is for John Dewey: His Approach To Education&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Montaigne: We take other men’s knowledge and opinions upon trust; which is an idle and superficial learning. We must make them our own. We are just like a man who, needing fire, went to a neighbor’s house to fetch it, and finding a very good one there, sat down to warm himself without remembering to carry any back home. What good does it do us to have our belly full of meat if it is not digested, if it is not transformed into us, if it does not nourish and support us?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/learning-vs-practicing&#34;&gt;Stop Thinking and Start Doing: The Power of Practicing More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engines4ed.org/hyperbook/nodes/NODE-224-pg.html&#34;&gt;Why Should We Learn By Doing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;purpose-practice&#34;&gt;Purpose practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.norvig.com/21-days.html&#34;&gt;The key is deliberative practice: not just doing it again and again, but challenging yourself with a task that is just beyond your current ability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Thomas Sterner, The Practicing Mind: When we practice something, we are involved in the deliberate repetition of a process with the intention of reaching a specific goal. The words deliberate and intention are key here because they define the difference between actively practicing something and passively learning it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;think-for-yourself-tfy-https-en-m-wikisource-org-wiki-on-thinking-for-oneself&#34;&gt;Think for yourself&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikisource.org/wiki/On_Thinking_for_Oneself&#34;&gt;TFY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OcdxW2XF0v8&#34;&gt;Get your brain back&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Schopenhauver: From all this it may be concluded that thoughts put down on paper are nothing more than footprints in the sand: one sees the road the man has taken, but in order to know what he saw on the way, one requires his eyes.&lt;br /&gt;
Wang Yin: 观看阅读别人创造的现成的内容, 能让人短暂的知道哪些东西是怎么实现的, 却不能让你获得创造那样内容的能力. 即便是看似最简单基础的内容都无法理清.&lt;br /&gt;
All by themselves my eyes put an end to all bookwormery, otherwise known as philology: I was released from the ‘book’, and read nothing more for years—the greatest favour I have ever done myself!That nethermost self, as if buried alive, as if made mute beneath the constant need to pay heed to other selves (—which is what reading is!) awoke slowly, shyly, hesitantly—but finally it spoke again. I have never been so happy with myself as in my life’s periods of greatest illness and pain: you need only take a look at Daybreak(Firo: also the dawn of day) or The Wanderer and His Shadow to understand what this ‘return to myself ’ was: the highest kind of recuperation!&amp;hellip; The other kind simply followed on from this. &amp;ndash; Ecce Homo Nietzsche, Why I write such good books, Review of Human, All Too Human section 4.(Firo: search bookwormery)&lt;br /&gt;
And &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/files/39955/39955-h/39955-h.html#toc1&#34;&gt;The Dawn of Day&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/files/37841/37841-h/37841-h.html#toc7&#34;&gt;The wanderer and his shadow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If he does not skim, he does not think. - Ecce Homo Friedrich Nietzsche, Why I Am So Clever, section 8&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;human-actions-and-practices-pattern&#34;&gt;Human actions and practices pattern&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;action-and-practice-structure&#34;&gt;action and practice structure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invariants: search goals and problems, goals, problems, actions, solutions&lt;br /&gt;
Material&lt;br /&gt;
Q = ( TfO * relevance(main root) * growing(past vs present structre, now structre) * Expanse ) / ( translation * Trivia * Irrelevancy)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems&#34;&gt;problems&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone can solve problems.Problems could be functionalties or goals.Problems could be optimizations which are better expressions of above functionalites or goals.Problems are structures(practices or actions?). Problems are growing upon others. Problems are growing structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;differences-between-reading-kernel-source-code-and-kernel-programming&#34;&gt;Differences between reading kernel source code and kernel programming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;creator/kernel hacking: 1. find problems; 2. problems; 3. create solutions 4. solutions&lt;br /&gt;
reader/reading codes: 1. translate(easy but less efficient way, reverse actions of creator) observings to problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;mistakes&#34;&gt;Mistakes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;海边度假问题&#34;&gt;海边度假问题&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;symbols&#34;&gt;Symbols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;problems: last node of linked list when iterating. problems from actions. don&amp;rsquo;t be fooled by symbols. linked list not &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;Richard Feynman - Names Don&#39;t Constitute Knowledge&#34;&gt;Feynman: Name of something vs something&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Collecting huge symbols without meaning is completely wasting time and life.&lt;br /&gt;
Symbols Authoritarianism&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;high-cost-doesn-t-mean-high-efficiency&#34;&gt;High Cost doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean high efficiency&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;subjectivity&#34;&gt;Subjectivity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Different minds; different behavoir; Relative minds. Writers are different to you. They don&amp;rsquo;t know wht you really want.&lt;br /&gt;
Vicariousness, Illusion of Competence&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;subjetive-and-relative-knowlodgy-theory&#34;&gt;Subjetive and relative knowlodgy Theory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schopenhauver on reading and books:We can never read the bad too little and the good too often.Inferior books are intellectual poison; they ruin the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-thing-and-out-observing&#34;&gt;In-thing and out-observing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creators are different to you, too. You are not only lack of what they created, but also ablities they used to create things. Unerstand vs create.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/knowledge-acquaindescrip/#Dis&#34;&gt;Knowledge by Acquaintance vs. Description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
return to myself vs made mute beneath the constant need to pay heed to other selves (which is what reading is!) &amp;ndash; Ecce Homo&lt;br /&gt;
nature grow, creation direction vs string search, artificial translation direction&lt;br /&gt;
vs 只有接受, 没有思维锻炼的机会.&lt;br /&gt;
process to &amp;lsquo;see&amp;rsquo;/experience vs symbols only&lt;br /&gt;
dependent knowledge, the underlying vs superfical knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
vs name of something, symbols&lt;br /&gt;
vs foreign to the drift and temper&lt;br /&gt;
causality vs reverse causalaity&lt;br /&gt;
vs 纸上得来终觉浅。 observation limited by symbols, named only.&lt;br /&gt;
Focus energy on goals. vs the wanderer, unlimited scope vague goals&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
