<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Philosophy on f(x) </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Firo Yang</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 20:23:11 CST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>荒野中的人</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/the_wilds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 20:23:11 CST</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/the_wilds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;国家是所有怪物中最为冷酷的, 冷酷的谎言从头的嘴里爬出来:&amp;ldquo;我, 这个国家, 就是全体人民.&lt;br /&gt;
                                ———— 尼采 《新的偶像》&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一个人在降生之前, 他的同类, 就以国家这个怪物的名义瓜分了这个他所赖以生存世界,&lt;br /&gt;
没有选择的余地. 是的, 无论你是否愿意, 你都将成为国家的一部分. 同时, 这也是&lt;br /&gt;
个人乃至整个人类族群的悲剧的起源!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人们不可避免的成为了社会的一个螺丝钉, 你要生存就必须参与进来.&lt;br /&gt;
生活在所谓社会中的个体, 又是怎样的? 普遍特征就是放弃思考!&lt;br /&gt;
在面对历经数千年历史形成的庞大社会体系, 对于个人来说, 了解适应&lt;br /&gt;
这个社会占据了他的一生. 只要少数人不断常识改变, 革新人们所处的生活&lt;br /&gt;
牢笼, 如卢梭, 孟德斯鸠, 尼采, 马克思等等.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我发现, 所处社会中绝大多数人, 都觉得他的being, 以及围绕他的一切都是理所当然.&lt;br /&gt;
所有的人, 都在顺从着社会的意志, 成为社会的奴隶. 而社会中的绝大多数人成为了一小部分&lt;br /&gt;
人的奴隶.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellecutual</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/intellectual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/intellectual/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most General and comprehensive type of inquiry(what is true and why)&lt;br /&gt;
Epistemology is theory of knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Metaphysics is the theory of reality.&lt;br /&gt;
Epistemic realism: the view that our knowledge is true of its objects independent of our ideas, theories, and cultures.&lt;br /&gt;
Antirealism/relativism: our true knowledge is made true not byobjects independent of us, but by our own ideas, perspectives, theories, and cultures.&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic philosophy:&lt;br /&gt;
Continental philosophy:&lt;br /&gt;
Pragmatism:&lt;br /&gt;
Tempered view:&lt;br /&gt;
Scholasticism: philosophy of the schools was based Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s logic and metaphysics; is essentially aristotle plus Christianity&lt;br /&gt;
Scholastic: what they did no have in their religious thouht was an elaborate complex theory of nature in the natural world.&lt;br /&gt;
Primary being/substance/the underlying:physical objects; contains parts but is not a pat of anything;properties are predicated of it, but it is not predicated of any thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Doctrine of the four causes: Aristotle generalize ideal objects, atomism to a very famous doctrine: the material, the efficient, the formal, the final.&lt;br /&gt;
Soul: the animating principle, not the Christian notion of soul, not an eternal ongoing non-physical essence.&lt;br /&gt;
Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s three levels of soul: 1 vegetative soul, characteristic of plants. 2. Moving-senstive-passionate soul, characteristic of animals. 3. rational soul, charteristic of .&lt;br /&gt;
CGN: the only way to udnerstand these objects in this world is to turn away from your experience of them, form how they look day to day and instead pay attention to an ideal mathematical reconstruction of those objects.&lt;br /&gt;
Rape of the senses: Morden science does not accord with our unaided senses, it accords with mathematical theory of potentially unobservable entities that explain our sense experience in the other words the new platonic but experimental science replaced the Aristotelian quanlitative and purpose of science that have become integrated whith Christian thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;descartes&#34;&gt;Descartes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archimedean point for all knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
Cogito ergo sum: I think, therefore I exist.&lt;br /&gt;
I: non-physical, thinking subsatnce.&lt;br /&gt;
extened substance/spatial extension&lt;br /&gt;
solipsist:&lt;br /&gt;
God must exists.&lt;br /&gt;
For Descartes, Reality is composed of:finite material substatnces, the essence of which is to take up space; finite mental substances, hunman minds and the human soul;on infinite mental substance, God.&lt;br /&gt;
Minds are non spatial thinking things without parts.Something without parts cannot come apart it can not decay. Imortal soul.&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes has thus provided a means a powerfull means of separating physical material reality which will noew be the province of the new science the materialist mechanical science of nature that comes especially from Galileo. The mind which is also the soul the seat of emotions which is also the seat of my own free will and hence responsible for ethics. It belongs to these fields and can&amp;rsquo;t be studied by science.&lt;br /&gt;
The best cognitive method God has given us we must be right otherwise God just is a deceiver.&lt;br /&gt;
The field of evidence presented to my individual mind is the foundation of all evidence for any claim.&lt;br /&gt;
Foundationalism: the belief that philosophy&amp;rsquo;s job jis to discover the foudndation or ground of all realist, objective knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;john-locke&#34;&gt;John Locke&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An essay concerning human understanding(1690)&lt;br /&gt;
an empty cabinet/a blank slate&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s basic categories(all possible properties that anything in the world can have): extension, solidity, motivity, mobility, perceptivity ot thinking, existence, duration, number.&lt;br /&gt;
Primary qualities: in the subject(in my mind) and in the object size, volume, mass, velocity, number.&lt;br /&gt;
Secondary qualities : color, taste, sound&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge: awareness of the agreement or disagreement of ideas with one another.&lt;br /&gt;
The awareness or knowledge comes in three different forms.&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition: the immediate recognition of the likenees or unlikeness of two ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
Senastion: feeling the entrance of ideas from sensation entering the mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Logical demostration or argument: Linking ideas together in such a way that there is a relationship of logical entailment or deduction.&lt;br /&gt;
 Unknown support.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s method: a posteriori; based on facts about the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes&amp;rsquo;s method: could not use a posteriori agruments because he had doubted the existence of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;berkeley&#34;&gt;Berkeley&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idealism: Reality is in some sense mental or the product of mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Interactions of mind and body:1. material events must be able to cause bodily and neural brain events. 2. Ideas in the mind must be able to represent things in the world that caused them; otherwise we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Ideas cannot represent material objects.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s Primary quailites: ideas in the mind taht represet and resemble the same quality in the material object, like zie&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s secondary qualities: caused by material events but don&amp;rsquo;t resemble them, like color.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke and Descartes: we perceive representations(ideas of things) outside our mind - representationalism&lt;br /&gt;
Berkeley: Where do representations exist? in our mind.&lt;br /&gt;
To be is to be percived.&lt;br /&gt;
Direct realism, the claim that we experience objects independent of the independent of the mind, is false.&lt;br /&gt;
Representationalism, the claim that we experience mental objects, but that these mental objects represent objects independent of the mind, is also false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;neo-aristotelians-spinoza-and-leibnizg&#34;&gt;Neo Aristotelians - Spinoza and Leibnizg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spinoza&#34;&gt;Spinoza&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole of everything: the only substance can be independent; the whole of existence is numerically one substance.&lt;br /&gt;
Immanent notions of God: somehow identify God with the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Transcendent notitons of God: see God as separate from the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Pantheist: an extreme form of immanentist.Infinite mentality and materialityand phisicality.&lt;br /&gt;
Panentheist: Nature is in God, but God is more than Nature. Spinoza.&lt;br /&gt;
Psychophysical parallelism: dimensions of the one. Mental events and physical events are co-ordinated in respectively minds and bodies.&lt;br /&gt;
Stoicism: apathy, apathos: the control of pathos, the control of emotion;&lt;br /&gt;
Ethics: magnum opus; the goal of human life and the highest state the mind can aspire to is a dispassionate intellectual love of God and a recognition of necessity and consequently as in Stoicism an internal state of calm acceptance rather than disturbed attachment to the faded events of this world. Spinoza is stauch critic of anthropomorphization of God. God can love this world but God has no free will and can not be conceived of as anything like a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;leibnizg&#34;&gt;Leibnizg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polymath, jack of all intellectual traists. Inaugurated the modern German philosophical tradition.&lt;br /&gt;
Monads: cannot causally interact; contain entelechy; phylogenetic thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Entelechy: an inner principle that unfolds all the changes it goes through with respect to other substances.&lt;br /&gt;
Bare monads: minimal appetition and perception.&lt;br /&gt;
souls: animal monads; cue ball is inanimate, but rabbit has soul.&lt;br /&gt;
Spirits: Monads with the property of apperception/统觉. essentially whtat that means is consciousness the ability to reflect on it&amp;rsquo;s own perceptions.SO here we have minds in our sense of the word(world?) that is human minds which capable of rational thought and they have a self now.&lt;br /&gt;
Space and time: continual and mere appearance; do not exist without the presence of monads.posthumous revenge on Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-enlightenment&#34;&gt;The Enlightenment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God said, &amp;ldquo;Let Newton be,&amp;rsquo; and there was light. - Alexander Pope&lt;br /&gt;
Encycolpedists&lt;br /&gt;
Spontaneous order: beneficial order that could be the product of undesigned activity: no one controls; only background rules govern independent action; no coordination among actions; beneficent order emerges.&lt;br /&gt;
Amour propre:the love of self as it is seen by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dvaid-hume&#34;&gt;Dvaid Hume&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of relations of ideas: the relations one idea bears to another in my mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge of matters of fact&lt;br /&gt;
Constant cojunction:Whenever A has occurred, B has occurred.&amp;ldquo;Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve seen smoke, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen fire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Necessary connection:If I say A and B are necesarily connected then I say not merely whenever A hsa occurred, B has occured. But I say Whenever A occurs B must occur: 1 whenever A occurs, A has the power to make B occur; 2 whenever A occurs in the future, B will occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;kant&#34;&gt;Kant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critique of pure reason:the theory of knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Critique of pratical reason: ethics.&lt;br /&gt;
Critique of judgment: aesthetics(theory of art), teleology(purpose in nature).&lt;br /&gt;
A priori: independent of experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Hume&amp;rsquo;s category of relations of ideas are both a priori and analytic.&lt;br /&gt;
Hume&amp;rsquo;s matters of fact are aposteriori and synthetic, or not true by definition.&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic: predicate conatained in subject&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic: predicate not in subject&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic a posteriori: Hume&amp;rsquo;s matters of fact; Belgium contains bachelors&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic a priori: Hume&amp;rsquo;s relations of ideas; All bachelors are unmarried.&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic apriori:non-trivial knowledge valid independent of experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Transcendental: the pre-structuring of experience by the mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Kant&amp;rsquo;s cognitive faculty:intuition, or sensibility, understanding, and reason.o&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition&amp;rsquo;s a priori forms: space, time&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding&amp;rsquo;s a priori categories: e.g., substances and their properties; necessary connection.&lt;br /&gt;
synthetic a priori knowledge: space,time;necessary connection; substance ( subject and predicate);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;karl-poper&#34;&gt;Karl Poper&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience or observations do not confirm scientific or inductive hypotheses. The function of induction is not to confirme; it is to disconfirm hpotheses.&lt;br /&gt;
Falsificationism: evidence really can&amp;rsquo;t confront any theory it can only falsify theory and this would mean that scientific claims are highly fallible&lt;br /&gt;
Fallibilism: All our judgments are fallible.&lt;br /&gt;
Physicalist reductionism: the view that all scientific knowledge should in principle be reducible to physics as the most basic science.&lt;br /&gt;
British Emergentists: the whole has properties that are more thatn so to speak to some of the parts and in effect what the emergence said was for example the properties of chemistry can&amp;rsquo;t be deduced from the properties of physical systems the properties of biology.&lt;br /&gt;
Positivism: quantum mechanics,&lt;br /&gt;
Supervenience: While any chage in mental events or properties must presuppose a change in nerual events or properties, the mental events or properties could still not be reduced to or explained by, neural events alone&lt;br /&gt;
Teleological causality: when a creature with a mind has an idea, and that idea has a causal relationship to what it does.&lt;br /&gt;
The structure of scientific revolutions: Whig interpertation of the history science&lt;br /&gt;
Prardigm: the fundamental concepts and practices of a science in a period of time.&lt;br /&gt;
Kuhn held that the meanings of the terms used in observation and theory in any period of normal science are dependent on that holistic paradigm&lt;br /&gt;
incommensurable: mutually untranslatable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pragmatism&#34;&gt;Pragmatism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;phenomenology&#34;&gt;Phenomenology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the things themselves.&lt;br /&gt;
bracketing: suspension of judgment.&lt;br /&gt;
eidetic reduction&lt;br /&gt;
transendental ego&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;derrida&#34;&gt;Derrida&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;semiosis: sign-using; the study of signs.&lt;br /&gt;
signs we use are arbitrary; signs are exterior or material -not solely mental.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>人类世界</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/human/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 15:46:11 CST</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/human/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;世界被他人的谎言所掩盖, 丧失了原始的存在欲望.`&lt;br /&gt;
一点点小的改变, 事情就会朝着好的方向发展.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一个人应该与外界的应该保持什么样的关系? 每个人都应该有自己的回答, 而且答案不一而终.&lt;br /&gt;
正是这种关系成就了我们的一生.个体如何确定这种关系,或者说如何确定一种合理的生存状态?&lt;br /&gt;
对于人类丰富, 无止尽的欲望而言, 很难给出统一的答案.然而这并不妨碍我们找到理想的状态.&lt;br /&gt;
简单说来, 两点; 那些来自内心的, 原始的, 本能的愿望正是我们生活的方向, 不应被忽视, 反而&lt;br /&gt;
要经常回忆起来, 并视若内心的珍宝一样对待; 另外, 我们应该做的是弥补生活中的不足, 以此来&lt;br /&gt;
向理想中的生活不断的迈进, 而不是沉醉于对理想的执着与等待中. 从实实在在的生活不足开始,&lt;br /&gt;
这才是真实的, 是你的生活.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;生活不在别处, 正是当下此地.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对于世界一部分的个体, 充分的认识世界的运作机制, 成为确定自己生活状态的前提. 对于普通人&lt;br /&gt;
而言, 这似乎无从下手. 尤其是对于处在巨大生存压力下的人, 无暇顾及这般如同象牙塔式的问题?&lt;br /&gt;
我想这正是他们生活悲剧的根源之一. 对于了解这个世界, 实际上要简单许多. 我想, 只要你有意识&lt;br /&gt;
地在遇到困惑, 疑问, 艰难, 令人不适的生活的时候, 寻找这些问题背后的原因的时候, 答案便会出现.&lt;br /&gt;
而答案就是一种关系, 因果律. 同时连带得出关系的主客体. 比如, 49年后, 中国人都有一个潜在&lt;br /&gt;
的伟大的身份, 社会主义建造者.这是个体和国家之间的某种答案,在我出生之时, 变自动获得这种身份.&lt;br /&gt;
直到我意识到这种身份的存在时, 我毫不犹豫的放弃了它.因为我并不是一个社会主义者,&lt;br /&gt;
我打心眼里抵触社会主义, 我很难想象他的存在, 同时那样的社会对我来说是一种无声的恐惧,&lt;br /&gt;
因为他偏离人性的核心, 那样的社会下的生活, 我一点也不期待, 我已体验过了.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;显然, 在人与世界的诸多联系中, 有一些是被他人赋予, 而那些强制赋予的很多都成了枷锁.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;对于确定生命个体的合理生存状态, 可以看成找到你与世界现有的关系以及想要的某种关系.&lt;br /&gt;
首先, 我们要理清那些重要的关系. 可以说我的哲学就是建立在关系之上, 也就是因果律.&lt;br /&gt;
人总生活在关系中, 我认为下面的关系很重要.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从个人角度, 越靠近真实, 越靠近真实, 不靠近就会远离. 这也是因果律的体现.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;即便你找不到期待中的生活状态，你也活在关系中, 这也是最基本的．&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人生没有目标, 也要好好活着!&lt;br /&gt;
所有人都是某些东西的奴隶 &amp;ndash; 进击的巨人&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其他的规律：&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;＞正反合&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 完整的逻辑,包含不存在&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 生活就是同傻逼的战争!&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 每个人都有自己内心的弱点, 不必害怕他们.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 生长需要滋润.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 成长开始于注意到缺陷, 疑问&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 很多时候其实我们的忙碌都是做着自己并不在乎的事情！&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;gt; 生命所不能承受之轻!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative congnition - The philosophy on which I am living</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am aware of that we need some principles and methods to understand this world.&lt;br /&gt;
The following thoughts try to help people to make a good life. They are out of my past life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;recognize-subjectivity&#34;&gt;Recognize subjectivity&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, you should know what is subjectivity and objectivity in philosophy.&lt;br /&gt;
In my opinion, subjectivity is the most important thing you should know then anything else.&lt;br /&gt;
Try to find when morden philosophy rose and why. Hint: read some works of Rene Descartes.&lt;br /&gt;
I found some bad effects of sujective mind:&lt;br /&gt;
* Deceptive objectivity. The worst case is it make you deem that unstanding is equivalent to doing.&lt;br /&gt;
* False target or procedure.(For English, 英语去学TTC的哲学课程, 和用英语与印度技术人员沟通, 这才是真正的目标, 而不是背单词,考试)(K2:以为看懂kernel, 就能做了)&lt;br /&gt;
* Deceptive understanding, wrong and absent(not excessive abstraction).&lt;br /&gt;
* shirk hardship, seek comfort and enjoyment.&lt;br /&gt;
* Frequently changing.&lt;br /&gt;
* Fading away along the time.&lt;br /&gt;
* Neglect objectivity.&lt;br /&gt;
* radical fallibility. &amp;ndash; Soros&lt;br /&gt;
* Overconfident subjective understanding. &amp;ndash; on larning kernel&lt;br /&gt;
* Subjective paralysis;Easy to perform and achieve in subjectivity makes objectivity lose interest.&lt;br /&gt;
* Flash across&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;thank-you-mr-feynman&#34;&gt;Thank you, Mr Feynman&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://archives.caltech.edu/pictures/1.10-29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;his blackboard at the time of death&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-did-Richard-Feynman-mean-when-he-said-What-I-cannot-create-I-do-not-understand&#34;&gt;What did Richard Feynman mean when he said, &amp;ldquo;What I cannot create, I do not understand&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://profizgl.lu.lv/pluginfile.php/32795/mod_resource/content/0/WHAT_IS_SCIENCE_by_R.Feynman_1966.pdf&#34;&gt;What is science by Feyman&lt;/a&gt;, do you know brown-throated thrush?&lt;br /&gt;
The Feynman Technique&lt;br /&gt;
* Record every obstacle&lt;br /&gt;
* Record every ability/knowledge in cs/pattern.log&lt;br /&gt;
* Thrive knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
* Proof by contradiction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;objective-understanding&#34;&gt;Objective understanding&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of the world./structuralism?&lt;br /&gt;
Learning by doing.&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition&lt;br /&gt;
Trial and error/Scientific method&lt;br /&gt;
Critical learning  &amp;ndash; Popper, Aaron Swartz 25:20&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Discourse_on_the_Method#Part_II:_The_principal_rules_of_the_Method_which_the_Author_has_discovered&#34;&gt;Descartes&amp;rsquo;s methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor&lt;br /&gt;
Reflexicity &amp;ndash; Soros/Statistics-based method training. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Transformation cognition &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Falsifiability &amp;ndash; Popper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad effects of Objectivity&lt;br /&gt;
* captivated by the objectivity, didn&amp;rsquo;t find the orign of world. (K2: 以为看过kernel绝大多数实现,样子就理解了kernel, 那只是更长的Feynman所说的名字, 是cramming)&lt;br /&gt;
* indirect false knowledge. fixed by genuine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;world-object-the-origins-of-the-world&#34;&gt;World/object/The origins of the world&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zur Sach selbst! &amp;hellip; to the things themselves!&amp;ndash; Husserl, Wittgenstein&lt;br /&gt;
* 不带有色眼光的, 看待事情知识本身. 别说什么你不感兴趣, 有些内容与计算机无关. 这都容易, 造成认知对象的消失, 从而偏见与盲目.&lt;br /&gt;
* From inspecting and examining the problem, if will help you to get the right method, not defrauded by the subjectivity. For english learning, not learning english but using english.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;真实, 实在. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
什么束缚. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Thrving knowledge. And roots, e.g. problem/ and how to use it, not how does it work.[The hidden knowledge/darkness 阻止了我们]&lt;br /&gt;
* Reading kernel book is looking the output of others&amp;rsquo;s minds. It&amp;rsquo;s something like &amp;lsquo;flash across&amp;rsquo;. So it&amp;rsquo;s fake of objectivity. That&amp;rsquo;s why I read kernel book. Reading is ok because of we are  Tabula rasa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macroscopic directed mind; Keep subjectivity and objectivity consistency;Whit of improving day by day. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know how to solve every problem that has been solved. &amp;ndash; Feynman&lt;br /&gt;
Nothing new under the sun.&lt;br /&gt;
小美好, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kohala.com/start/unpv12e.html&#34;&gt;take the programs, modify them and enhance them.&lt;/a&gt;  &amp;ndash; Stevens&lt;br /&gt;
Cthulhu, unkonw world, hard to measure, unfalsifiable, unreality, unfathomable, Indeterminacy, unmeasurable, imponderable,indefinite,&lt;br /&gt;
Repeat, irregularity, complexity&lt;br /&gt;
There is nothing permanent except change. ――Heraclitus&lt;br /&gt;
onset, nuclus, coda&lt;br /&gt;
Completeness, consistency, validity, soundness. &amp;ndash; Logic&lt;br /&gt;
The whole is other than the sum of the parts. &amp;ndash;Gestalt psychology&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
