<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Philosophy on f(x) </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Firo Yang</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 20:23:11 CST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>荒野中的人</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/the_wilds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 20:23:11 CST</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/the_wilds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;国家是所有怪物中最为冷酷的, 冷酷的谎言从头的嘴里爬出来:&amp;ldquo;我, 这个国家, 就是全体人民.&lt;br /&gt;
                                ———— 尼采 《新的偶像》&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一个人在降生之前, 他的同类, 就以国家这个怪物的名义瓜分了这个他所赖以生存世界,&lt;br /&gt;
没有选择的余地. 是的, 无论你是否愿意, 你都将成为国家的一部分. 同时, 这也是&lt;br /&gt;
个人乃至整个人类族群的悲剧的起源!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;人们不可避免的成为了社会的一个螺丝钉, 你要生存就必须参与进来.&lt;br /&gt;
生活在所谓社会中的个体, 又是怎样的? 普遍特征就是放弃思考!&lt;br /&gt;
在面对历经数千年历史形成的庞大社会体系, 对于个人来说, 了解适应&lt;br /&gt;
这个社会占据了他的一生. 只要少数人不断常识改变, 革新人们所处的生活&lt;br /&gt;
牢笼, 如卢梭, 孟德斯鸠, 尼采, 马克思等等.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我发现, 所处社会中绝大多数人, 都觉得他的being, 以及围绕他的一切都是理所当然.&lt;br /&gt;
所有的人, 都在顺从着社会的意志, 成为社会的奴隶. 而社会中的绝大多数人成为了一小部分&lt;br /&gt;
人的奴隶.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Architecture of Knowledge</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/knowledge/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;世界本源-the-origin-of-the-world-l-origine-du-monde&#34;&gt;世界本源, the origin of the world, L&amp;rsquo;Origine du monde&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;being(4), abyss(0)&lt;br /&gt;
material(1) change, quality, quantity, relation, inference&lt;br /&gt;
process(2)(5), tansfer, truth, signifier(3), bijection, Causality&lt;br /&gt;
simaotics, time-sharing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;以数学进制系统为例.貌似越为简约的计数系统, 只能越复杂,反之操作越为简单,原始.&lt;br /&gt;
或者说除一进制职位的计数系统, 其他都需要更为复杂?&lt;br /&gt;
 一进制对应双射! 其他是一对多.&lt;br /&gt;
本隐藏的识别系统.&lt;br /&gt;
我所理解人类思维行事习惯, 是建立在模式识别的基础上的. 很自然想到同理去制作computer.&lt;br /&gt;
这也是Turing machine所依靠的潜在前提.&lt;br /&gt;
而PC是建立在Bool Shannon的电子代数逻辑上的.&lt;br /&gt;
Arithmetic, 基础的 quantity change 规律.&lt;br /&gt;
algebra 求解未知process.&lt;br /&gt;
36 Turing machine.&lt;br /&gt;
我们如何评价computer中arithmetic用boolean algebra实现?&lt;br /&gt;
quantity -&amp;gt; quality, 这都是具体语义层面的概念.&lt;br /&gt;
首先, 要明确对于computer的adder来说,他在做得是elementary algebra不是简单的arithmetic,&lt;br /&gt;
而同时用于实现adder的是boolean algebra.&lt;br /&gt;
是什么是boolean algebra构建adder成为可能?&lt;br /&gt;
一个是qunatity, 一个是quality, 但采用相同的符号表达概念, 二者都是form system,&lt;br /&gt;
确是不同substance.只有0,1 的quantity和truth quality,在形式上等价,&lt;br /&gt;
我们先放下为什么computer不是从量这个角度构建.&lt;br /&gt;
那么logic的基本运算and, or, not又是什么呢?人为认知的quality的process or relation.&lt;br /&gt;
首先从一进制转换成二进制就已经违反人类的直观了.&lt;br /&gt;
一进制每个signifier(都相同)都有一个signified, bijection, one-to-one correspondence;抽象后lack of material.&lt;br /&gt;
二进制呢?signifier出现差异, 有两种0,1; 一进制可看成全是0,0&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;;&lt;br /&gt;
{,x, oo, ddd, ffff, &amp;hellip;}&lt;br /&gt;
一进制{, 0, 00, 000, 0000, &amp;hellip;}&lt;br /&gt;
二进制{0, 1, 10, 11, 100, 101, &amp;hellip;}&lt;br /&gt;
很显然, 一进制更符合我们对量的理解. 而二进制,就不那么直观了, 但是依然符合量的表述, 不过,&lt;br /&gt;
signifier的数量成2的指数所见. 同理16进制就更慢了.&lt;br /&gt;
检视adder的logic实现, 以1bit二进制数加和为例.&lt;br /&gt;
从量的视角, 一进制{,0,00}只有这三种可能.&lt;br /&gt;
二进制{0,1,10}, 我们人类如何计算二进制1 + 1呢?是一种模式匹配.&lt;br /&gt;
a + b &amp;lt; base , result = a + b; 如何a + b &amp;gt; base, result a + b - base;&lt;br /&gt;
如果我们使用电路但不是基于逻辑上的而是基于本质的运算规则. 我们规定相应的input的值和output值的关系.&lt;br /&gt;
0,0 -&amp;gt; 0&lt;br /&gt;
0,1 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br /&gt;
1,0 -&amp;gt; 1&lt;br /&gt;
1,1 -&amp;gt; 0, 1carry&lt;br /&gt;
电路怎么画呢?电路结构本身就是一种判断!&lt;br /&gt;
画完图, 我就明白了, 不是我们选择使用boolean algebra作为实现运算的手段, 而是我们别无选择, 或者说这种思维&lt;br /&gt;
过程, 正好被明明为了boolean 代数.&lt;br /&gt;
怎么实现一进制呢? a 有10中连接到reslt同b控制.&lt;br /&gt;
为什么进位制是有效的呢?反证法?&lt;br /&gt;
那这种进制计数法本质又是什么呢?一进制是纯粹的quantity语义, 而其他进制form system加入了顺序, 通过顺序表示quantity.&lt;br /&gt;
这也就是符号系统的表意能力, 又好比英语的word order. 顺序(排列)和元素种类是符号系统的signifier表意的重要关键.&lt;br /&gt;
留心到顺序与元素差异多少, 是唇亡齿寒的关系!&lt;br /&gt;
多进制系统已经不是纯粹量化关系了, 还涉及到了符号系统的表意层面, 也就是说要做判断(匹配).&lt;br /&gt;
二进制是扩大符号系统表意数量的, 而logic电路开关是构成符号系统表达能力的基本元素!&lt;br /&gt;
符号系统是有表达极限的!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;x代表0 or 1; x + x的数字电路logic实现:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0 不被理解-&amp;ldquo;冰冷安静&amp;rdquo;的世界。&lt;br /&gt;
1 An object is abstract (if and) only if it is causally inefficacious.&lt;br /&gt;
2 过程本身是有记忆的.&lt;br /&gt;
3 f(3)=4, 3是signifier, process or relation是f(x)=x+1 or f(x)=2x-2;&lt;br /&gt;
4 语言符号概念切割知识/being. 造成碎片成为理解的阻碍.人类的独特是能够感受的being.&lt;br /&gt;
5 由算法分析感知, 搞清变化与原因原因要比记住过程要vital. 过程的结果(不是最终结果,是每步的阶段)是他的因! 很美妙.&lt;br /&gt;
人对世界理解是建立在人对世界理解产生的概念之上, 这事把双刃剑. 被割裂的世界成为认知的&lt;br /&gt;
障碍. 成一种约束, 束缚.这个世界只要是能认知的,都被人类提上了标签. 恰恰因为这些标签,&lt;br /&gt;
割裂了二进制和boolean logic.知识本身成为了,知识自身发展的壁垒!人们建立沟壑, 同时又在&lt;br /&gt;
弥合这些沟壑. 也就是学到的知识本身,成为不可完全信任的存在了! sense experience成为重要认知手段.&lt;br /&gt;
在被割裂的前提下, 形式form成为了弥合沟壑的重要手段.&lt;br /&gt;
还有一点, Turing machine是建立在人为判断的基础上的. 而二进制的数字电路的这种判断能力是人为设计的.&lt;br /&gt;
我们可以称此二种判断为过程, 一个是通过光学转换成脑信号的过程, 一个是通过电流传到的过程.&lt;br /&gt;
那么为什么这两个复杂度天差地别的判断过程, 会形成相同的结果(在这里是完成计算二进制的1+1之类)呢?&lt;br /&gt;
虽然二进制数字电路无法完成, 眼睛光学信号到脑电流的附在转换过程.但是他们在能力上是完全等价的之于&lt;br /&gt;
computation 1+1, 这件事他们完成的是传递transfer这个世界本源.只要把相应符号送到相应process就可以了.&lt;br /&gt;
光学, 我们直接把1+1, 送到了1+1=0,1 carry.而二进制,我们是把1+1送到了a^b, a and b这两个过程中了.&lt;br /&gt;
判断本质是transfer.所以, 眼睛和电路完成了相同的功能&amp;ndash;transfer. 这里就是明显的概念割裂了知识,沟壑&lt;br /&gt;
使人难以预约, 最终通过形式form的一致(transfer)填补了沟壑.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;接下来是各种各样的&lt;br /&gt;
Computer science: learn how to formalize intuition about process, how to do things,&lt;br /&gt;
starting to develop a way to talk precisely about how-to knowledge, as opposed to&lt;br /&gt;
geometry talks about what is true.&lt;br /&gt;
Imperative knowledge: How to. guess is the 1st method. That&amp;rsquo;s a process as like a&lt;br /&gt;
magical spirit that sort of lives in the computer and does something.&lt;br /&gt;
Procedure directs a process is a pattern of rules. spells.&lt;br /&gt;
process is magical spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;process包含algorithms和更为基础的computation and else;&lt;br /&gt;
programming(design pattern) through language 是把这个process实例化.&lt;br /&gt;
os, architecture是作为process的辅助.&lt;br /&gt;
我觉得这里computation就类似语言的顺序和曲折变化这些最基本的elements.&lt;br /&gt;
并不是我们发现了hardware的计算能力, 而是hardware能完成我们的计算需求.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mathematics: Declartive knowledge, what is true. doesn&amp;rsquo;t really say anything about how&lt;br /&gt;
you might go out and find one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;根据依赖关系组织-展示的知识&#34;&gt;根据依赖关系组织, 展示的知识&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;知识之间都是相互依赖的.&lt;br /&gt;
Logic&lt;br /&gt;
Language&lt;br /&gt;
Mathematics&lt;br /&gt;
Programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English&lt;br /&gt;
Hibert提出23个问题. turing machine 是为了解决数学可判定性问题.&lt;br /&gt;
由此导致CS的蓬勃发展.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class of knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
Raw knowledge, which exists in live, is real, leisure, scattered, low chance to learn.&lt;br /&gt;
Raw knowledge need lots of time to learn.&lt;br /&gt;
Artificial knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
linear enumerate knowledge: only for searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phased objectives of learning knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellecutual</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/intellectual/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/intellectual/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;philosophy&#34;&gt;Philosophy&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most General and comprehensive type of inquiry(what is true and why)&lt;br /&gt;
Epistemology is theory of knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Metaphysics is the theory of reality.&lt;br /&gt;
Epistemic realism: the view that our knowledge is true of its objects independent of our ideas, theories, and cultures.&lt;br /&gt;
Antirealism/relativism: our true knowledge is made true not byobjects independent of us, but by our own ideas, perspectives, theories, and cultures.&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic philosophy:&lt;br /&gt;
Continental philosophy:&lt;br /&gt;
Pragmatism:&lt;br /&gt;
Tempered view:&lt;br /&gt;
Scholasticism: philosophy of the schools was based Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s logic and metaphysics; is essentially aristotle plus Christianity&lt;br /&gt;
Scholastic: what they did no have in their religious thouht was an elaborate complex theory of nature in the natural world.&lt;br /&gt;
Primary being/substance/the underlying:physical objects; contains parts but is not a pat of anything;properties are predicated of it, but it is not predicated of any thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Doctrine of the four causes: Aristotle generalize ideal objects, atomism to a very famous doctrine: the material, the efficient, the formal, the final.&lt;br /&gt;
Soul: the animating principle, not the Christian notion of soul, not an eternal ongoing non-physical essence.&lt;br /&gt;
Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s three levels of soul: 1 vegetative soul, characteristic of plants. 2. Moving-senstive-passionate soul, characteristic of animals. 3. rational soul, charteristic of .&lt;br /&gt;
CGN: the only way to udnerstand these objects in this world is to turn away from your experience of them, form how they look day to day and instead pay attention to an ideal mathematical reconstruction of those objects.&lt;br /&gt;
Rape of the senses: Morden science does not accord with our unaided senses, it accords with mathematical theory of potentially unobservable entities that explain our sense experience in the other words the new platonic but experimental science replaced the Aristotelian quanlitative and purpose of science that have become integrated whith Christian thought&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;descartes&#34;&gt;Descartes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Archimedean point for all knowledge&lt;br /&gt;
Cogito ergo sum: I think, therefore I exist.&lt;br /&gt;
I: non-physical, thinking subsatnce.&lt;br /&gt;
extened substance/spatial extension&lt;br /&gt;
solipsist:&lt;br /&gt;
God must exists.&lt;br /&gt;
For Descartes, Reality is composed of:finite material substatnces, the essence of which is to take up space; finite mental substances, hunman minds and the human soul;on infinite mental substance, God.&lt;br /&gt;
Minds are non spatial thinking things without parts.Something without parts cannot come apart it can not decay. Imortal soul.&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes has thus provided a means a powerfull means of separating physical material reality which will noew be the province of the new science the materialist mechanical science of nature that comes especially from Galileo. The mind which is also the soul the seat of emotions which is also the seat of my own free will and hence responsible for ethics. It belongs to these fields and can&amp;rsquo;t be studied by science.&lt;br /&gt;
The best cognitive method God has given us we must be right otherwise God just is a deceiver.&lt;br /&gt;
The field of evidence presented to my individual mind is the foundation of all evidence for any claim.&lt;br /&gt;
Foundationalism: the belief that philosophy&amp;rsquo;s job jis to discover the foudndation or ground of all realist, objective knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;john-locke&#34;&gt;John Locke&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An essay concerning human understanding(1690)&lt;br /&gt;
an empty cabinet/a blank slate&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s basic categories(all possible properties that anything in the world can have): extension, solidity, motivity, mobility, perceptivity ot thinking, existence, duration, number.&lt;br /&gt;
Primary qualities: in the subject(in my mind) and in the object size, volume, mass, velocity, number.&lt;br /&gt;
Secondary qualities : color, taste, sound&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge: awareness of the agreement or disagreement of ideas with one another.&lt;br /&gt;
The awareness or knowledge comes in three different forms.&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition: the immediate recognition of the likenees or unlikeness of two ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
Senastion: feeling the entrance of ideas from sensation entering the mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Logical demostration or argument: Linking ideas together in such a way that there is a relationship of logical entailment or deduction.&lt;br /&gt;
 Unknown support.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s method: a posteriori; based on facts about the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Descartes&amp;rsquo;s method: could not use a posteriori agruments because he had doubted the existence of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;berkeley&#34;&gt;Berkeley&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Idealism: Reality is in some sense mental or the product of mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Interactions of mind and body:1. material events must be able to cause bodily and neural brain events. 2. Ideas in the mind must be able to represent things in the world that caused them; otherwise we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Ideas cannot represent material objects.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s Primary quailites: ideas in the mind taht represet and resemble the same quality in the material object, like zie&lt;br /&gt;
Locke&amp;rsquo;s secondary qualities: caused by material events but don&amp;rsquo;t resemble them, like color.&lt;br /&gt;
Locke and Descartes: we perceive representations(ideas of things) outside our mind - representationalism&lt;br /&gt;
Berkeley: Where do representations exist? in our mind.&lt;br /&gt;
To be is to be percived.&lt;br /&gt;
Direct realism, the claim that we experience objects independent of the independent of the mind, is false.&lt;br /&gt;
Representationalism, the claim that we experience mental objects, but that these mental objects represent objects independent of the mind, is also false.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;neo-aristotelians-spinoza-and-leibnizg&#34;&gt;Neo Aristotelians - Spinoza and Leibnizg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;spinoza&#34;&gt;Spinoza&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole of everything: the only substance can be independent; the whole of existence is numerically one substance.&lt;br /&gt;
Immanent notions of God: somehow identify God with the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Transcendent notitons of God: see God as separate from the world.&lt;br /&gt;
Pantheist: an extreme form of immanentist.Infinite mentality and materialityand phisicality.&lt;br /&gt;
Panentheist: Nature is in God, but God is more than Nature. Spinoza.&lt;br /&gt;
Psychophysical parallelism: dimensions of the one. Mental events and physical events are co-ordinated in respectively minds and bodies.&lt;br /&gt;
Stoicism: apathy, apathos: the control of pathos, the control of emotion;&lt;br /&gt;
Ethics: magnum opus; the goal of human life and the highest state the mind can aspire to is a dispassionate intellectual love of God and a recognition of necessity and consequently as in Stoicism an internal state of calm acceptance rather than disturbed attachment to the faded events of this world. Spinoza is stauch critic of anthropomorphization of God. God can love this world but God has no free will and can not be conceived of as anything like a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;leibnizg&#34;&gt;Leibnizg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Polymath, jack of all intellectual traists. Inaugurated the modern German philosophical tradition.&lt;br /&gt;
Monads: cannot causally interact; contain entelechy; phylogenetic thing.&lt;br /&gt;
Entelechy: an inner principle that unfolds all the changes it goes through with respect to other substances.&lt;br /&gt;
Bare monads: minimal appetition and perception.&lt;br /&gt;
souls: animal monads; cue ball is inanimate, but rabbit has soul.&lt;br /&gt;
Spirits: Monads with the property of apperception/统觉. essentially whtat that means is consciousness the ability to reflect on it&amp;rsquo;s own perceptions.SO here we have minds in our sense of the word(world?) that is human minds which capable of rational thought and they have a self now.&lt;br /&gt;
Space and time: continual and mere appearance; do not exist without the presence of monads.posthumous revenge on Newton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-enlightenment&#34;&gt;The Enlightenment&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God said, &amp;ldquo;Let Newton be,&amp;rsquo; and there was light. - Alexander Pope&lt;br /&gt;
Encycolpedists&lt;br /&gt;
Spontaneous order: beneficial order that could be the product of undesigned activity: no one controls; only background rules govern independent action; no coordination among actions; beneficent order emerges.&lt;br /&gt;
Amour propre:the love of self as it is seen by others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;dvaid-hume&#34;&gt;Dvaid Hume&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge of relations of ideas: the relations one idea bears to another in my mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Knowledge of matters of fact&lt;br /&gt;
Constant cojunction:Whenever A has occurred, B has occurred.&amp;ldquo;Whenever I&amp;rsquo;ve seen smoke, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen fire.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Necessary connection:If I say A and B are necesarily connected then I say not merely whenever A hsa occurred, B has occured. But I say Whenever A occurs B must occur: 1 whenever A occurs, A has the power to make B occur; 2 whenever A occurs in the future, B will occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;kant&#34;&gt;Kant&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critique of pure reason:the theory of knowledge.&lt;br /&gt;
Critique of pratical reason: ethics.&lt;br /&gt;
Critique of judgment: aesthetics(theory of art), teleology(purpose in nature).&lt;br /&gt;
A priori: independent of experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Hume&amp;rsquo;s category of relations of ideas are both a priori and analytic.&lt;br /&gt;
Hume&amp;rsquo;s matters of fact are aposteriori and synthetic, or not true by definition.&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic: predicate conatained in subject&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic: predicate not in subject&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic a posteriori: Hume&amp;rsquo;s matters of fact; Belgium contains bachelors&amp;rsquo;&lt;br /&gt;
Analytic a priori: Hume&amp;rsquo;s relations of ideas; All bachelors are unmarried.&lt;br /&gt;
Synthetic apriori:non-trivial knowledge valid independent of experience.&lt;br /&gt;
Transcendental: the pre-structuring of experience by the mind.&lt;br /&gt;
Kant&amp;rsquo;s cognitive faculty:intuition, or sensibility, understanding, and reason.o&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition&amp;rsquo;s a priori forms: space, time&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding&amp;rsquo;s a priori categories: e.g., substances and their properties; necessary connection.&lt;br /&gt;
synthetic a priori knowledge: space,time;necessary connection; substance ( subject and predicate);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;karl-poper&#34;&gt;Karl Poper&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience or observations do not confirm scientific or inductive hypotheses. The function of induction is not to confirme; it is to disconfirm hpotheses.&lt;br /&gt;
Falsificationism: evidence really can&amp;rsquo;t confront any theory it can only falsify theory and this would mean that scientific claims are highly fallible&lt;br /&gt;
Fallibilism: All our judgments are fallible.&lt;br /&gt;
Physicalist reductionism: the view that all scientific knowledge should in principle be reducible to physics as the most basic science.&lt;br /&gt;
British Emergentists: the whole has properties that are more thatn so to speak to some of the parts and in effect what the emergence said was for example the properties of chemistry can&amp;rsquo;t be deduced from the properties of physical systems the properties of biology.&lt;br /&gt;
Positivism: quantum mechanics,&lt;br /&gt;
Supervenience: While any chage in mental events or properties must presuppose a change in nerual events or properties, the mental events or properties could still not be reduced to or explained by, neural events alone&lt;br /&gt;
Teleological causality: when a creature with a mind has an idea, and that idea has a causal relationship to what it does.&lt;br /&gt;
The structure of scientific revolutions: Whig interpertation of the history science&lt;br /&gt;
Prardigm: the fundamental concepts and practices of a science in a period of time.&lt;br /&gt;
Kuhn held that the meanings of the terms used in observation and theory in any period of normal science are dependent on that holistic paradigm&lt;br /&gt;
incommensurable: mutually untranslatable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pragmatism&#34;&gt;Pragmatism&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;phenomenology&#34;&gt;Phenomenology&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the things themselves.&lt;br /&gt;
bracketing: suspension of judgment.&lt;br /&gt;
eidetic reduction&lt;br /&gt;
transendental ego&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;derrida&#34;&gt;Derrida&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;semiosis: sign-using; the study of signs.&lt;br /&gt;
signs we use are arbitrary; signs are exterior or material -not solely mental.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative congnition - The philosophy on which I live</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;我正在常识建立一套量化认知体系. 为什么要做这件事? 无论是之于生命个体还是整个人类社会的演化总是依凭着对世界更深入, 更全面的认知. ? 正如Schlick 在General Theory of Knowledge 所言&amp;hellip; 而这种认知本身是什么呢? 在哲学上, Epistemology专门研究这个问题. 而我继续前人的工作.在过往的不断尝试中, 我体验与感悟到了, 这个世界很复杂, 不能有一些简单的规则来理解透.多种不同的角度, 往往是理解事物最合宜的方法.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;simple-model&#34;&gt;Simple model&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;认知的对象是simple的, 基于there is nothing new under the sun.&lt;br /&gt;
应为对于任何comprehensible的object, 他必然是commonplace, 应为nothing new.&lt;br /&gt;
这样的话, 一个人可以学会任何知识.如何量化他所学based on simple model.&lt;br /&gt;
既然所有知识, 都是简单的, 那么达到一定数量, 就显而易见的成为了衡量的标准.&lt;br /&gt;
那么是否, 我们&amp;rsquo;见的多了&amp;rsquo;, 就足够了呢? 以我个人学习kernel为例, 我看过很多的内核&lt;br /&gt;
source code, 我不觉得能很好理解我所看过的这些内容.&lt;br /&gt;
那么读代码本身是否必要呢? 就从理解这样的木来说,读代码不是必要的.我们的&lt;br /&gt;
目的是理解, 而不是读代码, 也就是说我迷失在代码中了.所以, quality, 更多的世界之源是&lt;br /&gt;
衡量我们知识的方面.也就是说, 很多人会接触到相同的东西, 但是理解的深刻, 多少是不一样&lt;br /&gt;
的.那么基于以上两点就够了吗?基于imperfect understanding, 我们知道不够.那么多次&lt;br /&gt;
多角度的理解, 就成为必要的了. 还有一点, 目标作为某种活动的副产品, 才是他本来的意义.&lt;br /&gt;
就好比, 要学英语, 如果用英语去学TTC的哲学课程, 和用英语与印度技术人员沟通.&lt;br /&gt;
这样才是真正寻找到目标的真正意义, we are not lacking of causality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantity&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality&lt;br /&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s like structuralism.&lt;br /&gt;
Stratal transverse Slicing&lt;br /&gt;
Origins of the world: teleological causality&lt;br /&gt;
Concurrency/prallel&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practial connection&lt;br /&gt;
Make a new one from scratch.&lt;br /&gt;
Impove the current one&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;world-object-the-origins-of-the-world&#34;&gt;World/object/The origins of the world&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;simple&lt;br /&gt;
Repeat, irregularity, complexity&lt;br /&gt;
There is nothing permanent except change. ――Heraclitus&lt;br /&gt;
onset, nuclus, coda&lt;br /&gt;
问题总是复杂的, 解决方法总是简单的.  &amp;ndash;xiaolai.li&lt;br /&gt;
Completeness, consistency, validity, soundness. &amp;ndash; Logic&lt;br /&gt;
The whole is other than the sum of the parts. &amp;ndash;Gestalt psychology&lt;br /&gt;
Falsifiability &amp;ndash; Popper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;oracle-machine-methods&#34;&gt;Oracle-machine/methods&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exposure and perception/feeling;&lt;br /&gt;
Exposure 解决的是人和世界/object隔离的问题, 也是任何object之间的联系多少的问题.&lt;br /&gt;
perception/feeling注重的是人和object对人所产生的感受的不同,导致不同的归宿.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Analyzing the object/goal/target&lt;br /&gt;
Things themselves - Husserl, Wittgenstein&lt;br /&gt;
Ideal goal directed thought. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Quantitative irregularity, Structural, and complexity analyzing. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
The question-based Feynman Technique&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the following method to select the appropriate methods&lt;br /&gt;
Reflexivity &amp;ndash; Soros&lt;br /&gt;
Transformation cognition &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Simple is long &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
The hot and important, else later. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Experiment and experience. &amp;ndash; Bacon, John Locke&lt;br /&gt;
2.1 Tips, implicity massive&lt;br /&gt;
Quantitative -&amp;gt; Statistics-based-&amp;gt; alloc time, excessive exposure&lt;br /&gt;
irregularity -&amp;gt; intuitional trial and err&lt;br /&gt;
regularity -&amp;gt; rational&lt;br /&gt;
Structural, -&amp;gt; rational, context, architecture&lt;br /&gt;
complexity -&amp;gt; rational. scientific method, Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;methods/&lt;br /&gt;
If massive and irregularity but simplicity&lt;br /&gt;
use firsthand massive exposed Trial and error or intuition&lt;br /&gt;
If massive not irregularity but complexity&lt;br /&gt;
use escartes&amp;rsquo;s and rational generative method&lt;br /&gt;
If massive simple regularity&lt;br /&gt;
use rational programish&lt;br /&gt;
Statistics-based method training. &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Occam&amp;rsquo;s razor&lt;br /&gt;
Scientific method&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;descartes-s-methods&#34;&gt;Descartes&amp;rsquo;s methods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Divide every question into manageable parts. &amp;ndash; Descartes&lt;br /&gt;
Begin with the simplest issues and ascend to the more complex. &amp;ndash; Descartes&lt;br /&gt;
Review frequently enough to retain the whole argument at once &amp;ndash; Descartes&lt;br /&gt;
Accept as true only what is indubitable. &amp;ndash; Descartes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;human-learning-architecture&#34;&gt;Human learning architecture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intuiation&lt;br /&gt;
Repeat, Neuroplasticity, Manas-vijnana&lt;br /&gt;
Sleep&lt;br /&gt;
Multitask: 互相启发, 幸亏没有等着背完GRE高频词,再练听力.&lt;br /&gt;
Active learning and Meaningful learning: Learning by DOing, Participating&lt;br /&gt;
Passive learning and Rote learning(cramming):我听, 我忘记; 我看, 有印象; 除了我做,我记住。&lt;br /&gt;
Trial and error: callback learning&lt;br /&gt;
Critical learning  &amp;ndash; Popper, Aaron Swartz 25:20&lt;br /&gt;
善假于物也. &amp;ndash; 荀子&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition&#34;&gt;Definition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;内涵定义: Genus-differentia definition 属加种差定义: 发生定义(设计), 关系定义, 功用定义, 摹状定义&lt;br /&gt;
充要定义, Real and nominal definitions&lt;br /&gt;
Classes of extensional definitions: enumerative definition&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://plato.stanford.edu/entries/definitions/&#34;&gt;Definitions Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection&#34;&gt;Reflection&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you can not think any further of somthing, you must be awarenees of lack of causilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;firo-subject&#34;&gt;Firo/subject&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;理性本身有界限, 意识到那些无法掌控的事, respect 生命本身.&lt;br /&gt;
Intuition&lt;br /&gt;
unpredictable untamed 20%, imperfect-understand, radical fallibility &amp;ndash; Firo, Soros, Popper&lt;br /&gt;
学习知识的重点, 不是知识现在是什么样, 也不是知识为什么这么样, 而是如果是你会是什么样的! &amp;ndash; Firo&lt;br /&gt;
Attention slavery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>日常生活中的偏见与谬误</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/bias_and_fallcy_in_daliy_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2015 15:46:14 CST</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/bias_and_fallcy_in_daliy_life/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;现代人的堕落-毫无建树&#34;&gt;现代人的堕落, 毫无建树&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;商业文化极端的引诱着人们的种种欲望, 人们沉溺在现代文明的娱乐文化中不能自拔;&lt;br /&gt;
犹如吸食大麻一般, 一味索取却毫无建树.这正是商业文化的真正目的, 永恒的消费者!&lt;br /&gt;
我将更多的从消费者转变成生产者. 人应该与自己气质, 期望相匹配, 否则便会痛苦.&lt;br /&gt;
远离现有的娱乐文化, 更多的输出和自我关心.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;被忽视的语言&#34;&gt;被忽视的语言&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;事物被还原到语言, 语言有概念构成.&lt;br /&gt;
设计从语言开始, 语言衍生各种创造的事物.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;offsenive-bias-and-causality&#34;&gt;offsenive bias and causality&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;代码是由用户需求而产生的.&lt;br /&gt;
之前学习内核的时候都是关注, 内核代码的组织实现,&lt;br /&gt;
没有想过为什么代码, 为什么产生, 着产生有什么好.&lt;br /&gt;
所谓因果律, 实乃胡适的历史的方法.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;不能看透&#34;&gt;不能看透&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;今天看机动战士z, 每个人物都在执着自己的理念, 不能一概而论,好与坏.&lt;br /&gt;
而相反, one piece, naruto一类人物的爱恨, 正邪分明.更确切的说,性格很单一.&lt;br /&gt;
我惊讶于自己, 觉察到这一点.&lt;br /&gt;
我开始思考事物的多样性了, 更多的可能.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;时间管理&#34;&gt;时间管理&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;时间管理的目标是事情不是时间.&lt;br /&gt;
关注点转换后, 更多关注todo, 而不是time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;生命中的永恒&#34;&gt;生命中的永恒&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;知识不会因为时间过期, 时间不能等效标注知识的有效性. 真正的道理是不随时间改变过时.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;发现存在&#34;&gt;发现存在&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>漂亮的话</title>
      <link>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Firo Yang</author>
      <guid>http://firoyang.org/philosophy/gallery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#Griffith&lt;br /&gt;
是的 就连一个国王也不能真正的随心所欲地生活 我们都只是随着命运的波浪漂流而已&lt;br /&gt;
直到我们最终离开这个世界 时间是有限的 而且命运在我们知道自己之前就会退去 在这个世界里 一定有一个人命中注定&amp;hellip; 无论他的社会地位和阶层如何 我一定要知道我在这个世界真正的身份是什么！我命中注定的东西到底是什么？&lt;br /&gt;
无谓的悲伤是没有用的&lt;br /&gt;
面对随时可能离去的生命&lt;br /&gt;
只有牢牢抓紧它不去浪费&lt;br /&gt;
才对得起昨日离开之人无限渴望的今日&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;梦想可以左右世界 可以让一个人一生而为之 很多梦想只能在孤独中苦苦寻求 而有些梦想则会在瞬间化为泡影 梦想能给人以支撑 也能带来巨大的苦痛&lt;br /&gt;
即使人被他的梦想所抛弃 仍然会有些东西是深深的郁结在他心中 每个人都应该为自己的梦想 去承受巨大的痛苦 至少一次 能够这样对待他们的生活&lt;br /&gt;
有些人认为生命不过是长时间的生活而后突然的死去 我从心底讨厌这种想法 也绝不认同它&lt;br /&gt;
我认为真正的朋友从不依赖他人的梦想 一个真正能成为我朋友的人 必须能靠自己而不是我的帮助 明白为了什么而生活 他必须全身心地投入&lt;br /&gt;
保护好他自己的梦想 必须毫不犹豫的为了自己的梦想而战斗 甚至是和我战斗&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我不能有遗憾和负罪感&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;想要实现广大而纯洁的梦想的人不可避免的要忍受可怕的事情 我们并非天生强大&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;我从你的眼中看到一些熟悉的东西 恐惧的味道 当一个人发现他十分恐惧的东西时 他会意识到不能坐视不管 不得不作出选择&lt;br /&gt;
要么屈服于恐惧的事物以求自保 要么消灭所害怕的事物来消除恐惧感&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;在这个空壳一样的世界 有一样东西清晰印在我的脑海中&lt;br /&gt;
每个人都很虚弱 因此我们紧紧地同我们的希望与梦想抱在一起 安慰也好 我渴望有人在我身边&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
